<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio, 2008-2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily lessons from London trains</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</guid>
      <description>For many people not living in the UK, it will come as a surprise that the railway system in London is quite expensive and provides a really bad service.
Train service is not a theme park. It affects people’s livesSome of my Spanish readers will think “surely that cannot be true”. After all, railway was born in the UK. And punctuality is probably one of the words when a Spaniard thinks of British people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King George III and the “rebellion”</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-05-25-king-george-iii-and-the-rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-05-25-king-george-iii-and-the-rebellion/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy buying books.
I read physical books too.I enjoy starting them.
Honestly, finishing books is more difficult for me. But I’ve been trying to improve on that.
I was very excited when I bought ‘1776&#39; by David McCullough. The title is a reference to the year when American Independence was proclaimed. However the book starts narrating in mid 1775 and ends at well into 1777, and it is more about the Rebellion/War for Independence in those years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a business: why?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-05-23-launching-a-business-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2018-05-23-launching-a-business-why/</guid>
      <description>I’ll start sharing a secret.
 I want to launch a business.Yes, I know many people in the tech industry are in the same situation. They’ve got some burning idea to launch or some dream to fulfil. A side-project going on for ages.
 I do have a number of brilliant ideas, at different stages (none of them complete). But most of the time a simply daydream while reading Twitter, or Hacker News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack Ma and laughing at ourselves</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2017-09-12-jack-ma-and-laughing-at-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2017-09-12-jack-ma-and-laughing-at-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>If you don’t know who is Jack Ma, he’s the founder and CEO of Alibaba, the marketplace and reportedly the richest person in Asia. I must confess he’s always amazing me. He’s a guy that it’s used to… If you don’t know who is Jack Ma, he’s the founder and CEO of Alibaba, the marketplace and reportedly the richest person in Asia.
I must confess he’s always amazing me. He’s a guy that it’s used to being rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess, trading and Bregret</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</guid>
      <description>When I was child, I used to play chess. From time to time you would find somebody that just had learned a special kind of opening and had decided to practice no matter what.
But having a plan is not enough. Chess involves thinking what could happen if things go different than planned. In a way a plan that not involves different alternatives is not a real plan.
I’ve been reading these days about trading: buying and selling shares and other instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2016-02-04-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2016-02-04-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I was listening a podcast aboutthe importance of being able to tell a story, not a lists of jobs when asked about you.
In a spirit of practising, I’m going to share two stories of my early life that affects who I am.
First, my family says I started to speak a bit late. But when I started to speak I did it almost like an adult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gifts</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-11-22-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-11-22-gifts/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday is next Friday, so that means Christmas is coming. All around will push us to buy things: food, clothing, gifts.
A couple of weeks ago we started receiving some catalogs from several different NGOs. The basic idea is you buy gifts. For people that need those gifts. For people you don’t know. And you receive a card.
My initial reaction was a bit of sadness. I feel, from a faith perspective, that there is kind of a buying craziness at this time of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil service: Why me?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-12-01-civil-service-why-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-12-01-civil-service-why-me/</guid>
      <description> A few days ago I promised to explain why I chose to become a civil servant, and why I keep being one. I was going to write about the challenge of a competitive examination, how challenges motivates me, and how my job keeps being interesting even though sometimes is a bit tough. But then I came to &#34;Reasons to work&#34;. Seth Godin. No more words needed. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community managers: The day after</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-02-03-community-managers-day-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-02-03-community-managers-day-after/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I followed on Twitter a case where the community manager for a -well known and with very good reputation- Spanish moving company&amp;nbsp;literally screwed up their reputation. He/she threatened to sue a customer that was expressing a complaint on Twitter, because the client had used the hash tag &#34;vergonzoso&#34; (shameful). IMO, the customer was not insulting and she was not threatening. Just complaining. Initially I thought about yet another tactic to be viral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright protection</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-08-16-copyright-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-08-16-copyright-protection/</guid>
      <description>You know something is broken with copyright when: You buy a &#34;Barbie and three Musqueteers&#34; DVD and you can&#39;t play in your DVD player because it&#39;s piracy protected. But... You download the same film from a P2P network, save to a CD and you can play it everywhere.
You can&#39;t install the Windows Vista that came with your computer, on a VirtualBox over a Linux box, because it refuses to activate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving in the UK</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-12-15-driving-in-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-12-15-driving-in-uk/</guid>
      <description>Today I rented a car for a few hours. I used to drive in Spain, but I hadn&#39;t driven since I came to London. I wanted to practice in not too stressful conditions before my family comes to visit me. Also I needed to buy some furniture.
There are two problems for a Spanish driver in the UK (actually for most drivers from outside of the UK).&amp;nbsp;
First. Cars have the steering wheel on the right hand side of the car, while outside the UK(overseas as they say) the steering wheel is on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-12-31-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-12-31-future/</guid>
      <description>More than six years ago I started this blog. I wanted to practice my English so that I would improve it. Four years laterI came to London and sort of abandoned it, thinking that working in an English speaking environment would be enough to practice. But it is not. I really think blogging is a good way to improve your written expression, to clarify your thoughts. And sometimes what you tell is worthwhile for others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good examples</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-05-09-good-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-05-09-good-examples/</guid>
      <description>I was made redundant at the end of March. It was a very stressful process but it ended up very well, as I&#39;ve been in my new job for almost a month and I&#39;m very happy. During process, I had to work with lots of recruiters. Both from inside and outside my former company. One thing many people in the recruiting industry fail to understand is that every interaction counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Christmas</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-12-25-happy-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-12-25-happy-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Happy Christmas and a wonderful 2015 to all of my readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lots of old friends</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-11-18-lots-of-old-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-11-18-lots-of-old-friends/</guid>
      <description>Yes. I know I was supposed to write about Civil service in Spain. But I&#39;ve promised myself to write a blog post Monday through Thursday. Nobody reads this, my head is full of memories, and I&#39;m not able to write about the planned topic. I could struggle with the it, but I prefer to write about my memories. In the last couple of days there&#39;s a lot of activity in my mailbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s resolutions ... in August</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2009-08-20-new-years-resolutions-in-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2009-08-20-new-years-resolutions-in-august/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on holidays, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had some spare time to stop and think. Last couple of months have been special. Some events have affected profoundly. One of those events has been the death of a collegue. Antonio was a young man. At least young for me, since he was in his early 40&amp;rsquo;s, only a few years older than me. Antonio was a nice guy. I remember him laughing a lot of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relocating to London</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-12-15-relocating-to-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-12-15-relocating-to-london/</guid>
      <description>In two weeks I will be working in London. I know I was expecting to continue my last post about Spring persistence. I have lots of things to write about the incredible experience of finding a job abroad and relocating. But as you&#39;ll imagine, I&#39;m quite busy. I&#39;ll try to post before starting in my new job, but I don&#39;t promise anything. Thank you. Each and every one of you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum for myself</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-08-16-scrum-for-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-08-16-scrum-for-myself/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I explained I have attended recently a couple of courses. One of them was about Scrum. The course was very interesting, although, as I explained in the evaluation, there were times when I wished there were only one teacher instead of three. At the end of the course, I took a test, and now I&#39;m Scrum Manager certified. I must say that the exam was quite difficult, but I don&#39;t consider myself a Scrum manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about Tecnimap 2010</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-09-30-some-thoughts-about-tecnimap-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-09-30-some-thoughts-about-tecnimap-2010/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a couple of days in Zaragoza (Spain), participating in Tecnimap 2010 last week. Tecnimap is a conference on IT for the Public Administration in Spain. I had presented a paper about one of the applications I manage: DocelWeb.
Overall it has been a nice experience, but I wanted to share some thoughts about it.
On a personal level, I think I was wrong in my planning. I planned to assist to few conferences and talks that I really wanted to assist, and scheduled the rest of the time for relationships and stands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring course</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-09-30-spring-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2012-09-30-spring-course/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m attending this week to a Spring Framework course. It&#39;s a very small class: the teacher, my boss and me. I don&#39;t consider myself slow, and neither is my boss. No, he doesn&#39;t read this blog. But we two were trying to keep up the frenetic pace the teacher is imposing. I had already used Spring, but up to now I didn&#39;t suppose who little did I know about Spring, about TDD, or even about Eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting over</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-10-13-starting-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-10-13-starting-over/</guid>
      <description>6 months since last post. These have been amazing ones. Lots of work to do. Lots of challenges. We left Mantis, now working with Redmine. Learning Ruby on Rails. And learning Grails for fun and for the job. I&#39;ve been studying for another competitive examination for a civil servant positon, but I wasn&#39;t motivated. Exam is next Saturday but I don&#39;t expect to pass I haven&#39;t had too much time to post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The passionate programmer</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-11-14-passionate-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2010-11-14-passionate-programmer/</guid>
      <description>The last few weeks have been really intense with respect to my career. I&#39;ve attended two courses, given some presentations, launched a few projects at work, and read some books. Sometimes I&#39;ve been under a lot of self-imposed pressure, but overall I&#39;ve learned a lot of things. One of the books I&#39;ve read has been really enlightening. It has been The passionate Programmer. It&#39;s a book I wish I&#39;d read years ago, and I&#39;m tempted to buy a few copies and give them to some of my coworkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think big</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-02-09-think-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-02-09-think-big/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I&#39;m not sure why, one of my daughters proposed to create a system to find cars inside garages at the shopping center. The car would locate itself using a GPS and then it would emit via radio. I told her that GPS waves don&#39;t go through the walls, and I tried to convince her to look for different approaches (like generating a wifi hotspot and using a mobile app, locate the car).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about a death</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2011-10-01-thoughts-about-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2011-10-01-thoughts-about-death/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you start to write because you need to write but you don&#39;t know what you want to express. This is one of those times.
A couple of days ago, a pregnant woman was killed, and another woman was wounded by a man in a church in Madrid and afterwards the man committed&amp;nbsp;suicide. Doctors performed a caesarean to the woman&amp;nbsp;assassinated&amp;nbsp;and the baby is alive. The man had a letter saying Satan was chasing him, and seems to be a homeless with police records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</guid>
      <description>Yes. It&amp;rsquo;s been three months since I wrote my previous post. When I started to write this blog I knew it could end like other blogs I have started. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I was going to stop writing so fast. In fact I have some other blogI write from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m not too persistent. I start things, because I have cool ideas. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have the guts to fight for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipping point</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-03-12-tipping-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2014-03-12-tipping-point/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy.&amp;nbsp;
I was developing a feature that allows to export from my showcase project Whendoigo to TripIt.&amp;nbsp;
I was using a gem from TripIt. A gem is kind of a library for Ruby (sort of jar for Java). The gem simply encapsulated the API from TripIt. But it was failing and apparently everything on my project was correct. So this time it didn&#39;t took me too long to start debugging the actual gem&#39;s code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What recruiters taught me about looking for a job</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-01-06-what-recruiters-taught-me-about-looking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/posts/2015-01-06-what-recruiters-taught-me-about-looking/</guid>
      <description>There are good recruiters. And there are bad recruiters. The good ones help you to find a job. The bad ones teach you how to look for a job. If you are looking for a job, be sure to do just the opposite of what the bad ones do. Almost every other day I receive an email offering me a position. &#34;Good for you&#34;.&amp;nbsp; No, bad for me. Most of the emails come from people I haven&#39;t spoken to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
