<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily lessons from London trains</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</guid>
      <description>For many people not living in the UK, it will come as a surprise that the railway system in London is quite expensive and provides a really bad service.
Train service is not a theme park. It affects people’s livesSome of my Spanish readers will think “surely that cannot be true”. After all, railway was born in the UK. And punctuality is probably one of the words when a Spaniard thinks of British people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>King George III and the “rebellion”</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-25-king-george-iii-and-the-rebellion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-25-king-george-iii-and-the-rebellion/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy buying books.
I read physical books too.I enjoy starting them.
Honestly, finishing books is more difficult for me. But I’ve been trying to improve on that.
I was very excited when I bought ‘1776&#39; by David McCullough. The title is a reference to the year when American Independence was proclaimed. However the book starts narrating in mid 1775 and ends at well into 1777, and it is more about the Rebellion/War for Independence in those years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a business: why?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-23-launching-a-business-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-23-launching-a-business-why/</guid>
      <description>I’ll start sharing a secret.
 I want to launch a business.Yes, I know many people in the tech industry are in the same situation. They’ve got some burning idea to launch or some dream to fulfil. A side-project going on for ages.
 I do have a number of brilliant ideas, at different stages (none of them complete). But most of the time a simply daydream while reading Twitter, or Hacker News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack Ma and laughing at ourselves</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-09-12-jack-ma-and-laughing-at-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-09-12-jack-ma-and-laughing-at-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>If you don’t know who is Jack Ma, he’s the founder and CEO of Alibaba, the marketplace and reportedly the richest person in Asia. I must confess he’s always amazing me. He’s a guy that it’s used to… If you don’t know who is Jack Ma , he’s the founder and CEO of Alibaba, the marketplace and reportedly the richest person in Asia.
I must confess he’s always amazing me. He’s a guy that it’s used to being rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess, trading and Bregret</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</guid>
      <description>When I was child, I used to play chess. From time to time you would find somebody that just had learned a special kind of opening and had decided to practice no matter what.
But having a plan is not enough. Chess involves thinking what could happen if things go different than planned. In a way a plan that not involves different alternatives is not a real plan.
I’ve been reading these days about trading: buying and selling shares and other instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-02-04-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-02-04-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I was listening a podcast aboutthe importance of being able to tell a story , not a lists of jobs when asked about you.
In a spirit of practising, I’m going to share two stories of my early life that affects who I am.
First, my family says I started to speak a bit late. But when I started to speak I did it almost like an adult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gifts</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-22-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-22-gifts/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday is next Friday, so that means Christmas is coming. All around will push us to buy things: food, clothing, gifts.  A couple of weeks ago we started receiving some catalogs from several different NGOs. The basic idea is you buy gifts . For people that need those gifts. For people you don’t know. And you receive a card.
My initial reaction was a bit of sadness. I feel, from a faith perspective, that there is kind of a buying craziness at this time of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil service in Spain: Job security</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-16-civil-service-in-spain-job-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 21:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-16-civil-service-in-spain-job-security/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a civil servant. Civil servants in Spain can&amp;rsquo;t be fired. Well, in fact they can be fired , but only because of extremely serious infringements , and after a complicated procedure.
This protection is intended to give security so that one civil servant can oppose employee&amp;rsquo;s chief orders if the employee thinks that what is being ordered is illegal. Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine I&amp;rsquo;m asked to delete certain documents in some repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The passionate programmer</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-14-passionate-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 17:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-14-passionate-programmer/</guid>
      <description>The last few weeks have been really intense with respect to my career. I&amp;rsquo;ve attended two courses, given some presentations, launched a few projects at work, and read some books. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ve been under a lot of self-imposed pressure, but overall I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot of things.
One of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read has been really enlightening. It has been The passionate Programmer . It&amp;rsquo;s a book I wish I&amp;rsquo;d read years ago, and I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to buy a few copies and give them to some of my coworkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting over</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-10-13-starting-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 18:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-10-13-starting-over/</guid>
      <description>6 months since last post. These have been amazing ones. Lots of work to do. Lots of challenges. We left Mantis, now working with Redmine. Learning Ruby on Rails. And learning Grails for fun and for the job.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying for another competitive examination for a civil servant positon, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t motivated. Exam is next Saturday but I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to pass
I haven&amp;rsquo;t had too much time to post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s resolutions ... in August</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-20-new-years-resolutions-in-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 22:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-20-new-years-resolutions-in-august/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on holidays, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had some spare time to stop and think.
Last couple of months have been special. Some events have affected profoundly.
One of those events has been the death of a collegue. Antonio was a young man. At least young for me, since he was in his early 40&amp;rsquo;s, only a few years older than me. Antonio was a nice guy. I remember him laughing a lot of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</guid>
      <description>Yes. It&amp;rsquo;s been three months since I wrote my previous post . When I started to write this blog I knew it could end like other blogs I have started. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I was going to stop writing so fast.
In fact I have some other blog I write from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m not too persistent. I start things, because I have cool ideas. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have the guts to fight for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-04-what-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-04-what-is-this/</guid>
      <description>Starting a blog it’s a difficult task. It’s not nearly as difficult as keeping updating it, of course.
I have started a couple of blogs.
Both are abandoned.
Not a good track.
Will this blog be different? I don’t know if I’ll continue updating this. But I know for sure this blog is different now.
The first difference is that I’m writing it in English. The reason I’m doing it, is because writing in English it’s an exercise for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
