<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily lessons from London trains</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-07-07-daily-lessons-from-london-trains/</guid>
      <description>For many people not living in the UK, it will come as a surprise that the railway system in London is quite expensive and provides a really bad service.
Train service is not a theme park. It affects people’s livesSome of my Spanish readers will think “surely that cannot be true”. After all, railway was born in the UK. And punctuality is probably one of the words when a Spaniard thinks of British people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Duplex and robocalls</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-12-google-duplex-and-robocalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-12-google-duplex-and-robocalls/</guid>
      <description>You’ve probably seen the video presentation about Google Duplex, the new assistant created by Google that can make phone calls that sound totally human interactions to the human on the other side (and to anyone listening).
If you haven’t, please go watch the 4 minutes version.
You can read more about it in this article . Not sure how this will work in real life.
But the demo looks amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Reality in macOS (II)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-27-virtual-reality-in-macos-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-27-virtual-reality-in-macos-ii/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; VR on macOS means beta, crashes, unusable WebVR, and no games. But you get to learn a lot. This post explains my experience.
It seems this time I’m one of the few non-professionals that has bought an HTC Vive and a Mac after June’s keynote. Not sure today, but three weeks ago I couldn’t find anywhere in the Internet what to buy, how to make it work, and what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Reality in macOS (I)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-12-virtual-reality-in-macos-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-12-virtual-reality-in-macos-i/</guid>
      <description>I have a two year old mid-level Android phone (Moto G 2015) not capable of using Google Cardboard . My tablet is an iPad Mini “1” with iOS9 because it can no longer be upgraded. My (old) computer was built from parts and it’s already 4 years old.
I love technology. And I’ve got a reasonable salary. But I’ve got a family and I’m very conscious about spending money.
However my latest acquisition suggests I’ve gone bonkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubble!!</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-07-22-bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-07-22-bubble/</guid>
      <description>In the late 90s there was some craziness in the air. Everybody perceived Internet was going to transform our lives. But we didn’t know how. Companies tried to grow at all costs, setting up what looked like crazy ideas. Money was being poured without any analysis.
Crypto investments being announced in a bus stop in the middle of London.I remember vividly that some people around me were trying to setup a startup, raise money with some vague promise, and be rich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disruption in Financial Services</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-06-28-disruption-in-financial-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-06-28-disruption-in-financial-services/</guid>
      <description>For many people, disruption in Financial Services are new banks that are building the platform from the ground up . Not being tied to legacy systems, make those banks easier to operate.
Don’t get me wrong. I’m a big fan of Monzo. Super fan of the notifications, their insights, and no fees when I go to my native Spain I pay with my coral card (Edit: I’m now even a proud user of their bank account)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix against the user</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-06-14-netflix-against-the-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-06-14-netflix-against-the-user/</guid>
      <description>I like Netflix. I really do. But there are a few things in their user interface that drive me crazy.
 You cannot remove a movie from continue watching. You’ve already watched a movie, don’t want to see the credits, butNetflix thinks you haven’t reached the end. Or you get bored of a movie half way. I even have a thumbs down on “Iron Fist” and it keeps appearing !!! How do you remove those movies you don’t want to keep watching?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the CTO is not management</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-05-17-when-the-cto-is-not-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-05-17-when-the-cto-is-not-management/</guid>
      <description>Tech startup founded by non-tech founders. Founders know little about technology, so they hire a CTO like they would hire an accountant. CTO is not part of management. Technology gets isolated. #### Choose your CTO… and then trust her
A friend of mine got hired as a CTO three years ago. What started as an exciting position setting up the whole team, technology and processes for the company, ended up sidelined, micromanaged, with no responsibility over the team, and no decision over the technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LetsEncrypt, Paypal and selling fear</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-03-30-letsencrypt-paypal-and-selling-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-03-30-letsencrypt-paypal-and-selling-fear/</guid>
      <description>There is a new report that associates Let’s Encrypt with phishing . So lots of people in Twitter started screaming because they read phishing and Paypal in the same sentence.
Let’s Encrypt is a foundation that gives certificates away for free. Not only that. Let’s Encrypt is trying to make installing and renewing a certificate effortless.
I decided to read the report which is more a blog post.
Apparently the argument of the report is that Let’s Encrypt doesn’t do a proper validation before giving away the certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the S3 outage</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-03-01-thoughts-on-the-s3-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-03-01-thoughts-on-the-s3-outage/</guid>
      <description>It’s in the news . Amazon S3, the popular object store crashed yesterday in one of their regions and affected multiple other sites, including Slack and GitHub .
So here are some comments about it:
 AFAICT the s3 outage was in us-east-1 region. Other regions didn’t have S3 affected. S3 in Europe* This is not the first s3 outage . You may have read about what this affects the 11 nines promise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fintech: Dinosaurs are doomed</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-10-04-fintech-dinosaurs-are-doomed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-10-04-fintech-dinosaurs-are-doomed/</guid>
      <description>I’m sick and tired of reading articles describing how the banks are going to buy the new players in Fintech.
Yes. It is going to happen. It has already happened. BBVA has already bought Simple and Atom . And it took them two years to start integrating Simple in a meaningful way.
However acquisitions are not going to change anything. And it is not because people in those banks don’t have a clue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumers need to understand…</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-17-consumers-need-to-understand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-17-consumers-need-to-understand/</guid>
      <description>Today I was reading this article about excuses from banks for crap services . Then I got to this sentence:
 Consumers need to understand that the balance you see is not necessarily your actual available balance because there are so many moving partsNo. Consumers don’t need to understand anything like that. It is your job to simplify things. And you even fail to recognise it.
 I’ve mentioned it before .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I hate my bank</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-15-i-hate-my-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-15-i-hate-my-bank/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was using my bank account, taking money out using a debit card. No way to see the operation since the feed only has old/settled operations. Since the available balance was below what I considered safe, I moved back the money using the same card.
Available balance didn’t change. And when days later, both operations were settled, one appeared in one day, the other the following day.
My bank allows me to do banking and investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Summit London 2016</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-07-aws-summit-london-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-07-07-aws-summit-london-2016/</guid>
      <description>Today I went to AWSSummit London . It’s a free event dedicated to Amazon Web Services. The event took place at Excel London , excellent venue except for the occasional noise due to planes taking off from the nearby London City Airport.
KeynoteThe day started with an intro from Gavin Jackson, expressing that there was a promise from Amazon for a new UK region for late 2016 or early 2017. And that promise continues after Brexit vote, and also thegeneral commitment from AWS with UK startup ecosystem .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I remember why I left “security”</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-27-now-i-remember-why-i-left-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-27-now-i-remember-why-i-left-security/</guid>
      <description>Around the year 2000, I was doing some consulting work for the ISP branch of a Spanish bank. I was creating dynamic web pages (not many people in the IT industry will remember the word CGI)
On my own, I discovered that creating dynamic we pages was tricky. Dynamic web pages require interacting with the user. But interacting with the user meant risking trusting the user.
Some examples I started taking a look to other dynamic web pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapchat: I’m getting old</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-20-snapchat-i-m-getting-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-20-snapchat-i-m-getting-old/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of months I’ve been able to see a growing trend with Snapchat. More and more people I follow in Twitter are testing Snapchat waters.
Around a month ago, I installed the app, started registering, think twice…
… and uninstalled.
Now, I’ve discovered that Snapchat is really a thing outside teenagers.
  And you know what?
 I don’t care.
I’m going to miss this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlphaGo, AI, and Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-13-alphago-ai-and-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-03-13-alphago-ai-and-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>I’m fascinated by AlphaGo. I truly am.
A week ago I knew nothing about go . Now, I’ve read the rules but I haven’t played a single game. So I’m left to commentators .
But, for me, we’re attending something historic .
I do think these matches mean Artificial Intelligence is nearer than I expected.
And, yes. With AI I mean self-aware, general (non-restricted to a domain) intelligence. What people in the domain call strong artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My take on #RIPTwitter</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-02-07-my-take-on-riptwitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-02-07-my-take-on-riptwitter/</guid>
      <description>There is some outrage in Twitter because it has started to implement some changes to its product.
 There was a change from stars to likes. I think I prefer stars because it conveys a different meaning: when I read something sad, I cannot click in Like, but I would click in star. Moments is something that appeared in the header of Twitter, but I haven’t clicked more than 3 times (the last one while preparing this post) Now it seems they’re going to put a “While you were away” on steroids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Netflix of books</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-12-12-the-netflix-of-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-12-12-the-netflix-of-books/</guid>
      <description>Broken Kindle anyone?A couple of months ago, we were flying back to London after the summer. My 12 year old twin daughters, usually eager video watchers or passionate console players, were avid readers at that moment. To the point they were sharing one of their two physical Kindle reading devices.
A woman walking along the aisle, stopped next to my wife, started a conversation with her about my daughters’ reading habits, and asked my wife what model of e-book reader we thought is better (so that she could give it to their own children).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving or dying</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-30-evolving-or-dying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-30-evolving-or-dying/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine sent to me a job offer. It caught both her and my attention because it shows a problem very common in Internet companies.
The company in question is quite successful in its niche. They have an IT platform based on LAMP/Wordpress stack. And they want to change to a new platform using technologies yet to define. So they are trying to recruit a Lead back-end developer to keep the old platform working while creating the new platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for FireOS</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-28-prepare-for-fireos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-11-28-prepare-for-fireos/</guid>
      <description>I was considering about buying one or two Amazon Fire, when I discovered they’re unlikely to come before Christmas.
Granted, the price is amazingly good. 50 quid was already good, so 35 is almost incredible. But, what the heck, this is the beginning of the season. And they’ve already run out of units?
There are several possibilities here:
 This is an strategy to create scarcity. “Buy now or you won’t have it” This is a massive screw-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love your users</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-10-19-love-your-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-10-19-love-your-users/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I was leading a small team in charge of developers’ tools and framework. We discovered a bug, and the easiest way to solve it was to make a change in a different piece of functionality that wasn’t technically right, but was being heavily used. The functionality had security issues, specially if improperly used, and it provided a shortcut to the proper way to do things.
So we had some discussion among team members, but it seemed a no-brainier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks and users</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-06-06-banks-and-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-06-06-banks-and-users/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I had an interesting discussion in Twitter about how a Spanish Government body (AEAT, the equivalent of HRMC in the UK or IRS in the US) was offering different “services” in two different websites.
For those not fluent in Spanish , think of going to one site to read email and going to a different site to write it.
Obviously, the experience was poor and confusing for the user, who doesn’t understand what is the pattern that puts a set of things under one address and a different set under a different one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think big</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-02-09-think-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 20:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-02-09-think-big/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, one of my daughters proposed to create a system to find cars inside garages at the shopping center. The car would locate itself using a GPS and then it would emit via radio. I told her that GPS waves don&amp;rsquo;t go through the walls, and I tried to convince her to look for different approaches (like generating a wifi hotspot and using a mobile app, locate the car).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android 4.4.3: Sony Xperia U</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-06-08-android-443-sony-xperia-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 21:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-06-08-android-443-sony-xperia-u/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago,I upgraded the firmware for my Sony Xperia U . It turns out that the place I used to download the firmware updates from, wasn&amp;rsquo;t providing new updates, so sometime ago, I migrated to a new source of firmware updates .
I knew that Cyanogenmod was already providing Over The Air (OTA) updates. What I didn&#39;t know is that today&#39;s update would bring Android 4.4.3 when even people with a Nexus 7 has not receive Google&#39;s update yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Macbook Pro&#39;s battery</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-05-29-maximizing-macbook-pros-battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 23:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-05-29-maximizing-macbook-pros-battery/</guid>
      <description>I have an old Dell Vostro 1720 and an Acer Aspire One AO110. Both are usable (and used), but have no battery.
So when I got my shiny brand new Mac, I decided I had to look after the battery.
And I read everything I could find about how to take care Macbook&amp;rsquo;s battery.
Apparently, old models used to need a periodic full discharge followed by a full recharge.
Apparently, that is no longer the case .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquisitions</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-03-15-acquisitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-03-15-acquisitions/</guid>
      <description>Today I wanted to talk about two acquisitions.
On one side, Facebook and Whatsapp. $19 billion. There are many different opinions. [Craziness](https://medium.com/enrique-dans/d5938c078376). [Logic](http://om.co/2014/03/03/whatsapp-vs-facebook/). IMO the money paid is crazy, but the deal has a lot of logic for Facebook. Because for many people around me (including teens), Whatsapp is THE social network. They(we?) share things like images and videos, status. We use it almost everyday. Food for thought: when was the last time you got to know anything reading it on Facebook?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techzing wives</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-09-20-techzing-wives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 20:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-09-20-techzing-wives/</guid>
      <description>I tend to listen Techzing podcast . It&amp;rsquo;s a podcast about very different topics, recorded by two geeks, (or developers, and entrepeneurs). I don&amp;rsquo;t remember when I started listening them. I do remember I started because I wanted to practice English and it was great (Justin is an Englishman and Jason is American). Soon I forgot why: they were great by themselves. The topics are very diverse from Technology, Entrepenurship, Politics (Loom and Gloom Report), Education, Genetics&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why LinkedIn breach is so important?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-06-07-why-linkedin-breach-is-so-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 22:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-06-07-why-linkedin-breach-is-so-important/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s widely spread that there has been a security breach in LinkedIn. At least there is a file with passwords in that social network. Even LinkedIn acknowledges it and suggests it will try to alert users whose passwords have been compromised.
We know that, and we know passwords were not in the clear (they were stored hashed), but they weren&amp;rsquo;t quite protected (they weren&amp;rsquo;t salted). My own password was on the file and had been &amp;ldquo;unhashed&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google, where are you going?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-05-14-google-where-are-you-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 15:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-05-14-google-where-are-you-going/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been Google fanboy for a long time. I remember the invitation for Gmail I received around mid-2004. Gmail was a revolution. From 50MB mail space at the time, they offered 1000MB (1GB). But the size wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only thing revolutionary. A great UI interface, faster than anything seen before was shocking.
I remember Google video chat. Being able to talk from the mail. &amp;ldquo;No installations&amp;rdquo;.
Even Google Wave was revolutionary although the launch was a big failure, and the project was more in Alpha than in Beta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When companies just don&#39;t get it</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-01-08-when-companies-just-dont-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 19:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-01-08-when-companies-just-dont-get-it/</guid>
      <description>I have a two years old Symbian cell phone and a second generation iTouch. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s enough to explain that until very recently I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay any attention at all to mobiles apps ads. Companies regularly announced new apps for the Apple Store (or the Android one), and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even read the announce. More recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started with mobile development . I have paid the Android and Apple fee, I have developed my own apps with PhoneGap and Appcelerator Titanium (games for my daughters, but nothing too serious).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first mobile application</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-12-04-my-first-mobile-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 19:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-12-04-my-first-mobile-application/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning some technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to write new, but they&amp;rsquo;re not new. I&amp;rsquo;m learning Ruby on Rails and mobile development. I still have to keep learning Java, and Grails, but I have a project in mind and I wanted to separate clearly from my day to day job, for lots of reasons. Some other day I&amp;rsquo;ll posts my thoughts about mobile development. But today I wanted to share that I have deployed my first application to my iTouch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about Tecnimap 2010</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-04-11-some-thoughts-about-tecnimap-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 15:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-04-11-some-thoughts-about-tecnimap-2010/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a couple of days in Zaragoza (Spain), participating in Tecnimap 2010 last week. Tecnimap is a conference on IT for the Public Administration in Spain. I had presented a paper about one of the applications I manage: DocelWeb . Overall it has been a nice experience, but I wanted to share some thoughts about it. On a personal level, I think I was wrong in my planning. I planned to assist to few conferences and talks that I really wanted to assist, and scheduled the rest of the time for relationships and stands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netbook Operating Systems</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-13-netbook-operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 22:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-13-netbook-operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I got a new Acer Aspire One A110. It&amp;rsquo;s an Atom N270 with 512 MB RAM and 8GB SSD hard disk and 8.9&#39;&#39; screen. It came with a personalized version of a Linux distribution called Linpus Lite based in Fedora 8. Since the first day I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing several Netbook OS and I wanted to share my thoughts about it.
  The original distribution, (as I&amp;rsquo;ve said) is a personalized version of Linpus Lite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo: A declining star (II)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-19-yahoo-declining-star-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-19-yahoo-declining-star-ii/</guid>
      <description>I wrote on the previous post that for a particular combination of search terms, Yahoo seemed to offer better results than Google . I read long time ago that in fact search was turning to be a commodity . I didn’t believe then, and I’m not convinced yet, despite the simple test I described on my post.
Anyway Yahoo has services that are (in my opinion) far better than Google’s. My favourite is a nearly unknown project called myweb , which could be said to be related to Google Bookmarks or Google Notebook .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo: A declining star(I)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-19-yahoo-declining-stari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-19-yahoo-declining-stari/</guid>
      <description>I like products coming from Google, and I’m usually less critic with Google’s errors than with others’. I use Google search, Gmail, Blogger… I even have a ridiculous financial position on Google (8 shares).
I’m a Google fan.
But I wasn’t conscious of how much I was a Google fan until I was preparing this post. I was getting ready to write about Yahoo’s CEO (Jerry Yang) resignation , and widening the scope, about Yahoo’s future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail and the future</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-16-gmail-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-16-gmail-and-future/</guid>
      <description>As I said on my last post, I think that integration of Video and voice chat could be part of a greater strategy . What would be that strategy?
In my opinion it should have two parts.
The first one would include the ability to search on your communications. Not only your written communications, but also your oral/video communications. The technology is not too far. We can today search on Youtube&amp;rsquo;s speeches , probably thanks to GOOG 411 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;The day Skype died&#39; revisited</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-12-day-skype-died-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-12-day-skype-died-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you realize you&amp;rsquo;ve written a weak post too late. It was my case with yesterday&amp;rsquo;s annotation .
I thought nobody would even read it. But it seems that, because of a trackback at Gmail Blog, I was wrong.
Fortunately, Matt Sealey (thank you, Matt), was kind enough to comment, pointing out one of the weakest parts. He says that Google&amp;rsquo;s movement only affects a portion of Skype&amp;rsquo;s services. With Gmail you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to call to real phones (he says &amp;ldquo;yet&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The day Skype died</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-11-day-skype-died/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-11-day-skype-died/</guid>
      <description>I read it first on Google Operating System , but I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen too much buzz on the blogs I follow.
For me today is the day Skype has definitively died.
Maybe it was long before from a pure bussiness view. There hasn&amp;rsquo;t been anything new since Skype&amp;rsquo;s adquisition by Ebay. And my contacts on Skype were offline most of the time lately.
But from now I don&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to even install Skype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MobuzzTV</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-10-mobuzztv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-10-mobuzztv/</guid>
      <description>I heard about MobuzzTV for the first time long time ago. I don&amp;rsquo;t watch news on TV, (I prefer to read than watch), so much less watch on the Internet. I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention then. From time to time, I read about Mobuzz on Enrique&amp;rsquo;s blog , but again I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention.
Last week MobuzzTV announced they would had to close unless they got 120,000 euros in donations .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
