<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demophilus wrote this…</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-11-18-demophilus-wrote-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-11-18-demophilus-wrote-this/</guid>
      <description>These days I’m reading a fascinating book on Roman History called SPQR . And I’ve discovered Roman History is full of lessons for today’s world.
As a small token, a line from Plautus , a Roman writer, that appeared in some of his books.
 Demophilus wrote this, Plautus barbarised it.As Mary Beard, the author of SPQR, explains, the sentence was a clever challenge.
 For people of Greek origin, it was a way to mock Romans, that didn’t bring anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess, trading and Bregret</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</guid>
      <description>When I was child, I used to play chess. From time to time you would find somebody that just had learned a special kind of opening and had decided to practice no matter what.
But having a plan is not enough. Chess involves thinking what could happen if things go different than planned. In a way a plan that not involves different alternatives is not a real plan.
I’ve been reading these days about trading: buying and selling shares and other instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Spanish  eGovernment law</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-11-new-spanish-egovernment-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-11-new-spanish-egovernment-law/</guid>
      <description>I was a Spanish Civil Servant from 2006 to 2012 (technically I&amp;rsquo;m still a Spanish Civil Servant on leave). I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for different branches of the Spanish Government from September 2000 to November 2012. Civil Service in Spain is reputed to be lazy among Spaniards. But having worked for all kind of employers (startups, multinationals, NGO and Government Agencies), I can say I&amp;rsquo;ve found lazy people there but I&amp;rsquo;ve also found engaged workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escrache</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-03-25-escrache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-03-25-escrache/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you´re a Member of Parliament. And you have decided you are not going to give your support to something. And then you get a group of people protesting against you.
 You would say. &#34;Well, nothing new&#34; &amp;hellip; calling you cockroach and threatening to kill you. 
You would say something like &#34;Well, you know. People sometimes say things they don&#39;t really think.&#34; ... at the street in front of your home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish budget deficit, 3Q2012</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-02-06-spanish-budget-deficit-3q2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 18:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-02-06-spanish-budget-deficit-3q2012/</guid>
      <description>From time to time I visit the page where the internal comptroller in Spain posts its budget deficit figures . Last week there was a link to the calendar of future publications. The calendar was last updated past September, and didn´t show anything for 2013. Usually at the end of January appears 3rd quarter budget deficit. So when January ended with no new data, I knew the figures would be bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Budget Deficit. What if ...?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-20-spanish-budget-deficit-what-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-20-spanish-budget-deficit-what-if/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: I&amp;rsquo;ve done again the calculations and are more unbelievable even. I won&amp;rsquo;t update this post but IMO it is quite reasonable to hit the target.
From time I tend to write about the Spanish budget deficit .
Almost nobody expects that Spain will meet its commitment around budget deficit for 2012.
Well. I want to say, that, regarding central government, I do think they are going to hit the target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June deficit was 8.54%</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-09-23-june-deficit-was-854/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 18:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-09-23-june-deficit-was-854/</guid>
      <description>From time to time I write about politics in Spain in general and in particular Spanish deficit. Sometimes I try to do some simple estimations and comments.
More recently there has been some comments in Spain regarding the [publication of regions&#39; budget deficit up to second quarter](http://www.minhap.es/Documentacion/Publico/GabineteMinistro/Notas%20Prensa/2012/SE%20PRESUPUESTOS%20Y%20GASTOS/13-09-12_PPT%20Ejecuci%C3%B3n%20Presupuestaria%20CCAA%20IITrim.pdf). But I&amp;nbsp;don&#39;t really understand why people insist to pay attention to [quarterly data without reference to a twelve month period](https://gonfva.blogspot.com.es/2012/03/estimating-spanish-budget-deficit.html). Let&#39;s do the math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Spanish budget deficit</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-03-29-estimating-spanish-budget-deficit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 13:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-03-29-estimating-spanish-budget-deficit/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my political/economical post (nothing related with computers) I write from time to time.
Past February, Spain published its estimation of whole year budget deficit.
Many well respected analysts suggested or explicitly wrote that maybe new Government was increasing 2011 deficit so that it could blame previous Government, and also in order to make it bigger so that it was easier to make it smaller. One for all, Xavier Xala i Martin :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget deficit</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-01-10-budget-deficit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 13:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-01-10-budget-deficit/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m talking about public data. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any unpublished data.
 In Spain there is some buzz recently about tax increases&amp;nbsp;approved&amp;nbsp;on December 30th. The government had changed and the new one said it was necessary to raise taxes because data said budget deficit where 8% GDP. The commitment was to finalize 2011 with a 6% GDP, from 9.2 previous year.&amp;nbsp; OK. Here is my take. We will end 2011 with more than 9% GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rain in Spain(II): Government</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-02-rain-in-spainii-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 21:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-02-rain-in-spainii-government/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with politics. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s less known abroad, but it&amp;rsquo;s probably more important than the economic situation. First the government. Forget about the past. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by the end. Today August 2nd 2011, one of the more complex days from an economic point of view for the hole world. Every stock market falling through like a knife in the butter. Spanish bonds at what lots of people understand as intervention level (400 basis points over German debt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rain in Spain(I)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-01-rain-in-spaini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 20:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-01-rain-in-spaini/</guid>
      <description>I love this video:
 A few days ago I received a message from one of my tweeps about the weather in Europe and in particular in Spain. This summer, the weather has been a bit strange so far. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help thinking about a different climate. The political and economical climate.
I know people outside Spain are worried about the situation in Spain. What can I tell about it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Emergency: very serious</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-12-04-state-of-emergency-very-serious/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 22:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-12-04-state-of-emergency-very-serious/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s in the news. Spanish Government has declared &amp;ldquo;State of Emergency&amp;rdquo; . This declaration gives special powers to the government like the ability to limit the circulation of people, commandeer things or even enter in private properties (but not homes) . It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat similar to State of Siege, but lower in intensity. Being Spain a democracy one could think that this kind of declaration should be reserved to extreme cases. That&amp;rsquo;s true in the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corruption</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-corruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 06:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-corruption/</guid>
      <description>Wow. It seems Wikileaks is going to publish some documents showing implication of some world leaders in corruption practices . I don&amp;rsquo;t have any other information but the Reuters piece of news.
I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have brought it to this blog if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the last paragraph of the first page:
Two of the sources said Assange has also made the documents available to at least two other European publications -- the newspapers El Pais of Spain and Le Monde of France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God help us</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I was wrong when I wrote last week&amp;rsquo;s post . Well, maybe I came to a rather good end result but for the wrong reasons:
  Income data from May 2009 (and probably June) was tricky because taxes returns were accelerated so that people could vote with their money back in the pocket.
  Data for income and expenses was only for the national services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lies, damn lies and statistics</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 22:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer. I&amp;rsquo;m not an economist or a statician, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any governmental internal information. I&amp;rsquo;m only a spaniard.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just read a piece of news about Moody&amp;rsquo;s considering Spanish outlook stable. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t foresee a default&amp;rsquo;s risk, I completely disagree. I think Spanish conditions are deteriorating very fast. I recommend reading this article on Moody&amp;rsquo;s decision.
Anyway, I remembered reading that in recent months Government&amp;rsquo;s income and expenses figures have been alarming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do for my country</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 22:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</guid>
      <description>And so, my fellow Americans: ask not what your country can do for you— ask what you can do for your country.
 A couple of weeks ago Jose Manuel Campa was nominated new Secretary of Economy in Spain. The position was being held by David Vegara, but he had expressed his intention to leave the job when his former boss Pedro Solbes was removed from the Ministry position.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
