<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demophilus wrote this…</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-11-18-demophilus-wrote-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-11-18-demophilus-wrote-this/</guid>
      <description>These days I’m reading a fascinating book on Roman History called SPQR . And I’ve discovered Roman History is full of lessons for today’s world.
As a small token, a line from Plautus , a Roman writer, that appeared in some of his books.
 Demophilus wrote this, Plautus barbarised it.As Mary Beard, the author of SPQR, explains, the sentence was a clever challenge.
 For people of Greek origin, it was a way to mock Romans, that didn’t bring anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess, trading and Bregret</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2016-06-26-chess-trading-and-bregret/</guid>
      <description>When I was child, I used to play chess. From time to time you would find somebody that just had learned a special kind of opening and had decided to practice no matter what.
But having a plan is not enough. Chess involves thinking what could happen if things go different than planned. In a way a plan that not involves different alternatives is not a real plan.
I’ve been reading these days about trading: buying and selling shares and other instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God help us</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I was wrong when I wrote last week&amp;rsquo;s post . Well, maybe I came to a rather good end result but for the wrong reasons:
  Income data from May 2009 (and probably June) was tricky because taxes returns were accelerated so that people could vote with their money back in the pocket.
  Data for income and expenses was only for the national services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lies, damn lies and statistics</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 22:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer. I&amp;rsquo;m not an economist or a statician, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any governmental internal information. I&amp;rsquo;m only a spaniard.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just read a piece of news about Moody&amp;rsquo;s considering Spanish outlook stable. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t foresee a default&amp;rsquo;s risk, I completely disagree. I think Spanish conditions are deteriorating very fast. I recommend reading this article on Moody&amp;rsquo;s decision.
Anyway, I remembered reading that in recent months Government&amp;rsquo;s income and expenses figures have been alarming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do for my country</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 22:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</guid>
      <description>And so, my fellow Americans: ask not what your country can do for you— ask what you can do for your country.
 A couple of weeks ago Jose Manuel Campa was nominated new Secretary of Economy in Spain. The position was being held by David Vegara, but he had expressed his intention to leave the job when his former boss Pedro Solbes was removed from the Ministry position.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
