<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m not considering your role</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-18-why-i-m-not-considering-your-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2018-05-18-why-i-m-not-considering-your-role/</guid>
      <description>Dear recruiter,
Thank you for contacting. At the moment I’m not looking for a job.
Kind regards,
Gonzalo
This is a bit impersonal.
I know. I’m sorry. The alternative is the above email for everyone.
You have some desired technologies under your belt.
Yes, I know.
Are you happy in your current job? Could you consider other roles?
Yes, I’m happy in my current job. Yes I could consider other roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad recruitment example 323234</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-10-30-bad-recruitment-example-323234/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-10-30-bad-recruitment-example-323234/</guid>
      <description>This is a story for my friend C. He didn’t know what was behind this old tweet
So I did a quick summary but I didn’t do the honours.
Here goes the detail. I won’t name the company (it’s bigco, a big company here in the UK).
The process started through a friend of mine that had joined BigCo. We had worked together and he wanted to work with me again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junior PHP developer</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-05-junior-php-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2017-08-05-junior-php-developer/</guid>
      <description>For the last month or so I’ve been running a small experiment in my Linkedin profile. I had been receiving contacts from recruiters offering roles, and from recruiters offering developers. I’m not quite interested in any of those services. Frankly, the job market for technology is a crazy house. Companies recruiting on readers of “Cracking the coding interview” instead of culture. Recruiters literally spamming or even sometimes harassing. And “candidates” either jumping for salary or just “getting a job”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear recruiter</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-08-15-dear-recruiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-08-15-dear-recruiter/</guid>
      <description>Dear recruiter. Don’t take it personal, but I’m not interested in the role you’re trying to recruit.
I receive lots of messages from recruiters. I get offered to participate in events so that companies can offer me new jobs.
I tend to reply something like:
Hi , Thank you for your message. However, at the moment I’m not interested in new opportunities. Kind regards, GonzaloI feel this kind of message does not explain the ultimate reason behind my reply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical tests</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-19-technical-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 19:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-19-technical-tests/</guid>
      <description>In March 2014 I was made redundant (business unit closing).
I needed to get a job and I participated in loads of selection processes. Sometimes I received feedback, sometimes not. But I remember two specific processes because I received completely different feedback from &amp;ldquo;technical tests&amp;rdquo; in a matter of days
Process A. Thanks for taking the time to complete our online testing. Unfortunately, your score did not meet the requirements of this role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What recruiters taught me about looking for a job</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-06-what-recruiters-taught-me-about-looking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2015-01-06-what-recruiters-taught-me-about-looking/</guid>
      <description>There are good recruiters. And there are bad recruiters. The good ones help you to find a job. The bad ones teach you how to look for a job.
If you are looking for a job, be sure to do just the opposite of what the bad ones do.
Almost every other day I receive an email offering me a position.
&amp;ldquo;Good for you&amp;rdquo;.
No, bad for me.
Most of the emails come from people I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multithreading: Warning lights</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-01-21-multithreading-warning-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 12:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-01-21-multithreading-warning-lights/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I went to an interview which included a pair programming session. The session was a great experience, but the result wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as good as it should have been, because of some difficulties understanding on what was being asked. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help it was my first experience working with a Mac.
At one point we agreed on creating a new constructor so that we could pass a service in the constructor instead of getting directly in the method under test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companies, developers and recruitment</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-08-companies-developers-and-recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 09:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-08-companies-developers-and-recruitment/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I reported my business unit was offered for sale. Not much to report about it (I know very little and I can write even less)
Obviously, most of us in the business unit, decided to brush up our Linkedin pages and get into the job market, just in case.
I remember in particular one interview. It didn&amp;rsquo;t start well when I replied &amp;ldquo;Sí, I mean, yes&amp;rdquo; after listening my name with a perfect Spanish z sound (as it turned out, one of the interviewers was Spanish too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-08-30-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 18:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-08-30-changes/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago my company sent out this press release. It seems to be rather unimportant, but for me it means changes.
I work for that specific business unit. I cannot write too much. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t know too much, but also because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to tell too much. But there are some topics I would like to raise.
In Spain, if your work is good and the company is doing great, whatever happens in between, has little importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great experience applying to a position (II)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-14-a-great-experience-applying-to-position_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 22:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-14-a-great-experience-applying-to-position_14/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I explained a great experience applying for a position. In this post I wanted to share what lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt from that experience.
Selection: Be very selective about what you apply for. For me this means no recruiters, making a pre-research of the company, and reading carefully the description to get a sense of what the company is asking. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious, but essential for the following lesson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great experience applying to a position (I)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-13-a-great-experience-applying-to-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 21:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-13-a-great-experience-applying-to-position/</guid>
      <description>I wrote in my last post about lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve got from bad experiences looking for a job. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about a good experience I had last week, how much I learnt from it, and the lessons I got from it. Make no mistakes: I didn&amp;rsquo;t get offered the position in the end.
For me, the outcome is not the most important thing in such a process, but the feeling you&amp;rsquo;re not losing your time, and the lessons learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad experiences</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-12-bad-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 21:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-12-bad-experiences/</guid>
      <description>For some time I&amp;rsquo;ve been applying to different positions. I have two daughters and I want for them (and for me) to live in a different culture and language. After a few experiences, I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to say something about bad experiences:Forget about recruiters. They have different alignments than yours. In my experience (it could be biased), 90% of them are just form fillers. They ask you things (CV, tests, questions), in order to fill a form in a random web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-07-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-07-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I read a couple of posts not directly related, and I start to think about a topic I didn&amp;rsquo;t expected.
This time, it all started with a post of Enrique Dans.
Enrique asked what happens when your company is looking for new employees, enters a professional social network like Linkedin to find the right person for the job, and discover that you have a completely updated profile, showing that in a way you’re &amp;ldquo;in the market&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
