<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>This blog on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/this-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in This blog on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 08:00:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/this-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Future</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-12-31-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 08:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2014-12-31-future/</guid>
      <description>More than six years ago I started this blog. I wanted to practice my English so that I would improve it.
Four years laterI came to London and sort of abandoned it, thinking that working in an English speaking environment would be enough to practice.
But it is not. I really think blogging is a good way to improve your written expression, to clarify your thoughts. And sometimes what you tell is worthwhile for others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of this blog</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-13-the-future-of-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 19:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-13-the-future-of-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>When I started this blog, I had a goal. I needed to practice my English, because I wanted to go abroad. Months (or even years) later, more reasons appeared. First, I discovered that writing about solutions to job related problems could give people a way to solve their own problems more easily. Later on, I realized it could also be a way to show that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a newcomer while looking for a position abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three months later</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-02-14-three-months-later/</guid>
      <description>Yes. It&amp;rsquo;s been three months since I wrote my previous post. When I started to write this blog I knew it could end like other blogs I have started. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I was going to stop writing so fast.
In fact I have some other blog I write from time to time. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m not too persistent. I start things, because I have cool ideas. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have the guts to fight for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this?</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-04-what-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2008-11-04-what-is-this/</guid>
      <description>Starting a blog it’s a difficult task. It’s not nearly as difficult as keeping updating it, of course.
I have started a couple of blogs.
Both are abandoned.
Not a good track.
Will this blog be different? I don’t know if I’ll continue updating this. But I know for sure this blog is different now.
The first difference is that I’m writing it in English. The reason I’m doing it, is because writing in English it’s an exercise for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
