<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spain on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/spain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spain on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 18:23:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/categories/spain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>God help us</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-09-03-god-help-us/</guid>
      <description>It turns out that I was wrong when I wrote last week&amp;rsquo;s post . Well, maybe I came to a rather good end result but for the wrong reasons:
  Income data from May 2009 (and probably June) was tricky because taxes returns were accelerated so that people could vote with their money back in the pocket.
  Data for income and expenses was only for the national services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lies, damn lies and statistics</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 22:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-08-27-lies-damn-lies-and-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer. I&amp;rsquo;m not an economist or a statician, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any governmental internal information. I&amp;rsquo;m only a spaniard.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just read a piece of news about Moody&amp;rsquo;s considering Spanish outlook stable. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t foresee a default&amp;rsquo;s risk, I completely disagree. I think Spanish conditions are deteriorating very fast. I recommend reading this article on Moody&amp;rsquo;s decision.
Anyway, I remembered reading that in recent months Government&amp;rsquo;s income and expenses figures have been alarming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do for my country</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 22:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2009-05-26-what-can-i-do-for-my-country/</guid>
      <description>And so, my fellow Americans: ask not what your country can do for you— ask what you can do for your country.
 A couple of weeks ago Jose Manuel Campa was nominated new Secretary of Economy in Spain. The position was being held by David Vegara, but he had expressed his intention to leave the job when his former boss Pedro Solbes was removed from the Ministry position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil service in Spain: Job security</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-16-civil-service-in-spain-job-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-16-civil-service-in-spain-job-security/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a civil servant. Civil servants in Spain can&#39;t be fired. Well, in fact they can be fired, but only because of extremely serious infringements, and after a complicated procedure. This protection is intended to give security so that one civil servant can oppose employee&#39;s chief orders if the employee thinks that what is being ordered is illegal. Let&#39;s imagine I&#39;m asked to delete certain documents in some repository. If I worked in a company and I don&#39;t do delete them, I could be fired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil service in Spain: Productivity</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-17-civil-service-in-spain-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-17-civil-service-in-spain-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I wrote yesterday about why job security is a good mechanism to protect civil service from corruption. But I also explained that it&#39;s a mechanism that makes difficult to punish slackers. That wouldn&#39;t be a serious problem if there were mechanism to reward people who do right. And the truth is that there aren&#39;t. The salary has a variable part but could be more or less explained as &#34;if you come to work twice a week in the afternoon, you get it&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil service: How to improve</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-civil-service-how-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-civil-service-how-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I promised to explain some of my ideas to improve the civil service in Spain. Of course there is no silver bullet. Instead, as you can see the links, all the bricks are in place: Try to introduce economic incentives. People who work should be rewarded. Of course that could be misused to give more money to friends instead of giving it to the people who work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corruption</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-corruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2010-11-25-corruption/</guid>
      <description>Wow. It seems Wikileaks is going to publish some documents showing implication of some world leaders in corruption practices. I don&#39;t have any other information but the Reuters piece of news. I wouldn&#39;t have brought it to this blog if it weren&#39;t for the last paragraph of the first page: Two of the sources said Assange has also made the documents available to at least two other European publications -- the newspapers El Pais of Spain and Le Monde of France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Emergency: very serious</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-16-state-of-emergency-very-serious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-08-16-state-of-emergency-very-serious/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s in the news. Spanish Government has declared &#34;State of Emergency&#34;. This declaration gives special powers to the government like the ability to limit the circulation of people, commandeer things or even enter in private properties (but not homes).
It&#39;s somewhat similar to State of Siege, but lower in intensity. Being Spain a democracy one could think that this kind of declaration should be reserved to extreme cases. That&#39;s true in the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rain in Spain(I)</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-01-rain-in-spaini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-01-rain-in-spaini/</guid>
      <description>I love this video:  A few days ago I received a message from one of my tweeps about the weather in Europe and in particular in Spain. This summer, the weather has been a bit strange so far. But I couldn&#39;t help thinking about a different climate. The political and economical climate. I know people outside Spain are worried about the situation in Spain. What can I tell about it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rain in Spain(II): Government</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-02-rain-in-spainii-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2011-08-02-rain-in-spainii-government/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s start with politics. I guess it&#39;s less known abroad, but it&#39;s probably more important than the economic situation. First the government. Forget about the past. Let&#39;s start by the end. Today August 2nd 2011, one of the more complex days from an economic point of view for the hole world. Every stock market falling through like a knife in the butter. Spanish bonds at what lots of people understand as intervention level (400 basis points over German debt).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
