<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>London on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/london/</link>
    <description>Recent content in London on Gonzalo&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Gonzalo Fernandez-Victorio {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 09:56:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gonzalo.f-v.es/tags/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Companies, developers and recruitment</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-11-companies-developers-and-recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 09:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-11-companies-developers-and-recruitment/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I reported my business unit was offered for sale . Not much to report about it (I know very little and I can write even less)
Obviously, most of us in the business unit, decided to brush up our Linkedin pages and get into the job market, just in case.
I remember in particular one interview. It didn&amp;rsquo;t start well when I replied &amp;ldquo;Sí, I mean, yes&amp;rdquo; after listening my name with a perfect Spanish z sound (as it turned out, one of the interviewers was Spanish too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-01-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-11-01-one-year/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I was in a plane flying into London. I was in whirl, nearly panicking. My life about to change.
I&amp;rsquo;m somebody who loves being in his comfort zone. And then leaving your wife and daughters for 6 months. Leaving your country for who knows how much time.
It has been hard. There have been difficult times. In lots of different levels. Renting in London (well worth a million pages book).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-08-30-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 18:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-08-30-changes/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago my company sent out this press release . It seems to be rather unimportant, but for me it means changes.
I work for that specific business unit. I cannot write too much. Because I don&amp;rsquo;t know too much, but also because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to tell too much. But there are some topics I would like to raise.
In Spain, if your work is good and the company is doing great, whatever happens in between, has little importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IKEA vs Greenwich</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-07-19-ikea-vs-greenwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 12:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2013-07-19-ikea-vs-greenwich/</guid>
      <description>This post started as a way of comparing different ways of managing customer relationships. It ended up as rant, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to delete it. But I will write another post in the future with some suggestions.
A good experience: IKEA. I recently bought some furniture from IKEA, using their online services in the UK. The furniture was delivered on Friday morning, and in the evening I discovered that there was package less than expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving in the UK</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-15-driving-in-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 19:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-15-driving-in-uk/</guid>
      <description>Today I r[ented a car for a few hours](http://www.zipcar.com/). I used to drive in Spain, but I hadn&#39;t driven since I came to London. I wanted to practice in not too stressful conditions before my family comes to visit me. Also I needed to buy some furniture. There are two problems for a Spanish driver in the UK (actually for most drivers from outside of the UK).&amp;nbsp; First. Cars have the steering wheel on the right hand side of the car, while outside the UK(overseas as they say) the steering wheel is on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relocating to London</title>
      <link>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-15-relocating-to-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 19:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gonzalo.f-v.es/blog/2012-12-15-relocating-to-london/</guid>
      <description>In two weeks I will be working in London. I know I was expecting to continue my last post about Spring persistence . I have lots of things to write about the incredible experience of finding a job abroad and relocating.
But as you&amp;rsquo;ll imagine, I&amp;rsquo;m quite busy. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to post before starting in my new job, but I don&amp;rsquo;t promise anything. Thank you. Each and every one of you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
